[
  {
    "name": "Introduction",
    "icon": "book",
    "difficulty": "CEFR A1",
    "description": "Learn basic grammar and vocabulary",
    "unit": [
      [
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "han",
          "tip": "If there is no subject, verbs are assumed to be in the third person.",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "han",
            "translation": "he/she/it is"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "she is",
          "answers": ["han"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han",
          "answers": ["to be", "to exist", "be", "he is", "she is", "it is"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "symi",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "han symi",
            "translation": "he is a man"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "symi",
          "answers": ["a man", "man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "he is a man",
          "answers": ["han symi"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "cévo",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "han cévo",
            "translation": "she is a woman"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "a woman",
          "answers": ["cévo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "náu",
          "tip": "Adjectives will always come before nouns",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "náu cévo",
            "translation": "a tall woman"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "náu symi",
          "answers": ["a tall man", "tall man", "a big man", "big man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "She is tall",
          "answers": ["han náu"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han náu symi",
          "answers": ["he is a tall man", "he is a big man", "it is a tall man", "it is a big man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "mikol",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "han mikol symi",
            "translation": "he is a short man"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "mikol symi",
          "answers": ["a short man", "short man", "a small man", "small man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "it is small",
          "answers": ["han mikol"]
        }
      ],
      [
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "ny",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "ny han náu",
            "translation": "I am tall"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "it is me",
          "answers": ["han ny"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "ké",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "ké han cévo",
            "translation": "you are a woman"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are me",
          "answers": ["ké han ny"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "I am a woman",
          "answers": ["ny han cévo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han ké",
          "answers": ["he is you", "she is you", "it is you"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ké han mikol",
          "answers": ["you are short", "you are small"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "I am a woman",
          "answers": ["ny han cévo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "téu",
          "tip": "It may not be used as a subject of a sentence.",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "han téu",
            "translation": "it is him/her"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "he is him",
          "answers": ["han téu"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han náu",
          "answers": ["he is tall", "she is tall", "it is tall", "he is big", "she is big", "it is big"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ny han mikol",
          "answers": ["I am short", "I am small"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "she is short",
          "answers": ["han mikol"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ké han",
          "answers": ["you are", "you exist"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "it is me",
          "answers": ["han ny"]
        }
      ],
      [
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ny han mikol",
          "answers": ["I am short", "I am small"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han náu",
          "answers": ["he is tall", "she is tall", "it is tall", "he is big", "she is big", "it is big", "he is large", "she is large", "it is large"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "ċo",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "ċo han",
            "translation": "we exist"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ċo han náu",
          "answers": ["we are tall", "we are big", "we are large"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "we are short",
          "answers": ["ċo han mikol"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are us",
          "answers": ["ké han ċo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "vun",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "vun han",
            "translation": "you exist"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you all are tall",
          "answers": ["vun han náu"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "vun han mikol",
          "answers": ["you are small", "you all are small", "you are short", "you all are short"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ny han téu",
          "answers": ["I am him", "I am her", "I am it"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "it is us",
          "answers": ["han ċo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "we are short",
          "answers": ["ċo han mikol"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "sojón",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "ké han sojón",
            "translation": "you are kind"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are kind",
          "answers": ["ké han sojón", "vun han sojón"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ċo han sojón",
          "answers": ["we are nice", "we are kind"]
        }
      ],
      [
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ċo han sojón",
          "answers": ["we are nice", "we are kind"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han mikol",
          "answers": ["it is short", "it is small"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "we are nice",
          "answers": ["ċo han cévo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are her",
          "answers": ["ké han téu"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han vun",
          "answers": ["it is you", "she is you", "he is you", "it is you all", "she is you all", "he is you all"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "he is a man",
          "answers": ["ny han symi"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "it is us",
          "answers": ["han ċo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han ké",
          "answers": ["it is you", "he is you", "she is you"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ké han symi",
          "answers": ["you are man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are kind",
          "answers": ["vun han sojón", "ké han sojón"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ny han téu",
          "answers": ["I am him", "I am her", "I am it"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han cévo",
          "answers": ["it is a woman"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are me",
          "answers": ["ké han ny", "vun han ny"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ny han náu",
          "answers": ["I am tall", "I am big", "I am large"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "han vun",
          "answers": ["it is you", "it is you all"]
        }
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Basics I",
    "icon": "bridge-circle-exclamation",
    "difficulty": "CEFR A1",
    "description": "Learn the definite article and negation",
    "unit": [
      [
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "i",
          "tip": "[i] may turn adjectives into nouns",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "i cévo han sojón",
            "translation": "the woman is kind"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "i symi",
          "answers": ["the man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "i náu",
          "answers": ["the tall thing", "the big thing", "the large thing", "the tall one", "the big one", "the large one"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "she is the woman",
          "answers": ["han i cévo"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ny han i symi",
          "answers": ["I am the man"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "nes",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "i nes",
            "translation": "the thing"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "nes han náu",
          "answers": ["a thing is tall", "thing is tall", "a thing is big", "thing is big", "a thing is large", "thing is large", "an object is tall", "object is tall", "an object is big", "object is big", "an object is large", "object is large"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "the thing is",
          "answers": ["i nes han"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "vé",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "i cévo vé han nes",
            "translation": "the woman has a thing"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "i symi vé han nes",
          "answers": ["the man has a thing"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "vé han nes",
          "answers": ["he has a thing", "she has a thing", "it has a thing", "he has an object", "she has an object", "it has an object"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "she has a man",
          "answers": ["vé han symi"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "the man has a short thing",
          "answers": ["i symi vé han mikol nes"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "i sojón han ny",
          "answers": ["the kind thing is me", "the nice thing is me", "the kind one is me", "the nice one is me"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you are the tall one",
          "answers": ["ké han i náu"]
        }
      ],
      [
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "the tall thing is tall",
          "answers": ["i náu han náu"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "vé han i sojón",
          "answers": ["he has the kind thing", "she has the kind thing", "it has the kind thing", "he has the nice thing", "she has the nice thing", "it has the nice thing"]
        },
        {
          "type": "vocabulary",
          "word": "miro",
          "example": {
            "sentence": "ny vé han miro",
            "translation": "I have bread"
          }
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "ċo vé han miro",
          "answers": ["we have bread", "we have a loaf of bread"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "you have the bread",
          "answers": ["ké vé han i miro", "vun vé han i miro"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "native-new",
          "prompt": "the bread is small",
          "answers": ["i miro han mikol"]
        },
        {
          "type": "short-response",
          "direction": "new-native",
          "prompt": "i nes han miro",
          "answers": ["the thing is bread", "the thing is a loaf of bread", "the object is bread", "the object is a loaf of bread"]
        },
        {
          "type": "match",
          "new": ["miro", "cévo", "symi", "han"],
          "native": ["bread", "woman", "man", "to be"]
        }
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Basics II",
    "icon": "file-circle-question",
    "difficulty": "CEFR A1",
    "description": "Learn question words and question form",
    "unit": []
  },
  {
    "name": "Basics III",
    "icon": "walkie-talkie",
    "difficulty": "CEFR A1",
    "description": "Learn everyday phrases",
    "unit": []
  },
  {
    "name": "Vocabulary I",
    "icon": "clipboard-check",
    "difficulty": "CEFR A1",
    "description": "Learn more basic vocabulary",
    "unit": []
  }
]
